multisafepay.com 2019-07-01

# MultiSafepay: Privacy & cookies

## Who is MultiSafepay?

MultiSafepay operates as a payment service provider and processes a large amount of data from customers (merchants using the MultiSafepay payment services) and the customers of our customers (i.e. consumers). Therefore it is of primary importance to MultiSafepay to process data - particularly personal/sensitive data - with the greatest care and the highest possible level of security. MultiSafepay will take necessary steps to guarantee and safeguard secure data processing. 

Please note that in this document, we may refer to MultiSafepay as “we” and to the data subject (the entity of which data is processed) as “you”. In this privacy policy, we will disclose all relevant information regarding the processing of data by MultiSafepay. 

## How does MultiSafepay process personal data? 

We process the data for different reasons. Generally, your personal data is processed because you use our services or because you provided this information to MultiSafepay yourself. MultiSafepay primarily processes data for purposes of fraud prevention and to provide products and services. All data processing activities are described in this privacy policy. 

We process different categories of data. MultiSafepay is required to be compliant with laws and regulations applicable to the payment industry, e.g. anti-money laundering laws (Wft and WWft). The data categories we process may vary, depending on your relationship with MultiSafepay. You can be one of our customers (“merchant”), one of our customers’ consumers (“consumer”), or you can be one of our website visitors. 

Please note that it is possible to have more than one relationship with MultiSafepay simultaneously.  E.g. you can be a merchant, a consumer of one of our merchants, and a visitor of our website at the same time. If you want to know which categories of data we may process, please read below. 

## Why does MultiSafepay process personal data?

We process personal data for the following reasons:

  * To process transactions, e.g. when a consumer orders products in online shop that uses the MultiSafepay payment platform.
  * To offer products and services
  * To evaluate your application if you want to become a MultiSafepay customer (merchant)
  * To contact you, e.g. when you use an online form to receive more information, request a quote, etc. The personal data is processed in order to perform and process these actions related to our services. 
  * To send you relevant information and marketing communication. MultiSafepay believes in good e-commerce and in sharing information, this is why we may send you pertinent information. You can opt out at any time. 
  * To train MultiSafepay employees. 
  * To perform analyses (for statistical purposes)

## What kind of consumer data does MultiSafepay process?

If you are one of our merchant’s costumers (i.e. a consumer), the following personal data may be processed: 

  * Personal details, e.g. name, date of birth, nationality, address, phone number, email address
  * IP address
  * Browser and/or device used (e.g. laptop, tablet, smartphone)
  * Other personal data which is actively provided to MultiSafepay (e.g. in correspondence or telephone conversations)

## What kind of merchant data is processed by MultiSafepay? 

If you MultiSafepay merchant, the following personal data may be processed: 

  * Personal details, e.g. name, date of birth, nationality, address, phone number, email address
  * IP address
  * Browser and/or device used (e.g. laptop, tablet, smartphone)
  * Other personal data which is actively provided to MultiSafepay (e.g. in correspondence or telephone conversations)

## Does MultiSafepay process sensitive personal data?

MultiSafepay needs to process sensitive data in order to perform its core business: processing payments. The processing of data is performed with the greatest care. 

MultiSafepay has no intention to collect and process information about minors visiting the MultiSafepay website, even if permission to visit the website has been granted by a parent and/or guardian. Unfortunately, MultiSafepay cannot verify the age of website visitor. We therefore recommend that parents and/or guardians monitor their child's online activities carefully in order to prevent the processing of minors' data. 

If you, in spite of the provisions mentioned above, feel that MultiSafepay processed sensitive personal data in a unlawful way, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://www.multisafepay.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#a7c3c6d3c6d7d5c8d3c2c4d3cec8c9e7cad2cbd3ced4c6c1c2d7c6de89c4c8ca "Opens internal link in current window") and report it. MultiSafepay will subsequently take steps to have the data removed as soon as possible. 

## Data collection of website visitors

Our website uses cookies. Cookies are a standard internet technology which enables us to store certain login information and directly connect with the system of the user. Cookies cannot be used to identify individuals, only machines. Each visitor can set up his/her computer to prevent cookies from being accepted. If you are one of our website visitors, we will process different information about your behavior online and use cookies. 

We call information about your online behavior: location data, details about activities on the website, IP address, internet browser, device used, etc. 

MultiSafepay may utilize different kinds of cookies:

  *  **First-party cookies.** Cookies sent to your browser from our website.
  *  **Third-party cookies.** Cookies sent to your browser from a domain or a page managed by another entity. Consequently, the data processed from those cookies is also managed. 
  * **Session cookies.** Cookies uniquely used during a visit to our website, i.e. data processed is ephemeral and will expire after a short amount of time. 
  * **Permanent cookies**. Cookies drawn to process data for a longer period of time. They persist after the duration of the web navigation, after closing the browser and shutting off the computer. Permanent cookies process data persistently for a longer period of time. 
  * **Analytical cookies.** Cookies used solely for statistics. They allow us to analyze the number of visits, frequency, device(s) used, size of screen etc. Thanks to the use of analytical cookies, we can create customized content for you and improve our services and products. 
  * **Google Analytics.** We use cookies with Google Analytics in order to statistically evaluate the MultiSafepay website. 

## How to opt out from cookies?

You can always opt out from some or all cookies. In order to administrate the cookies, you can use the configuration panel of your browser.  

## How long do we store your data? 

The amount of time that data is stored, depends on the purpose of data collection. Generally speaking, data will be retained for the mandatory statutory period or for the period required for the realization of the objectives (purposes stated before in this policy). Please note that in some cases,a mandatory statutory persiod does not apply. Additionally, the law may require or permit the retention of certain data categories for a longer period of time. Consequently, some data will be stored beyond the termination of the statutory period. 

The information required to process your application to process payments will be stored no longer than seven years after termination of your account or agreement (e.g. due to obligations of data retention as imposed by third parties such as taxes, etc.). Your data may be shared with third parties if so required to uphold the agreement between a customer and MultiSafepay. In case it is required for the fulfillment of the agreement or for any legal obligation, your data will be shared with third parties. We share your data with carefully chosen third parties, with whom we entered a written agreement for the secure, controlled, limited, careful and lawful processing of data. This is why, we can ensure the third party will process data with a high level of security and high care. 

In case your data will be shared with a third party beyond the reasons stated above, you will be notified and asked for your explicit consent. 

## Your Rights

Under the new European General Data Protection Regulation, also known as the GDPR (EU) 2016/679, you have the right to view, limit, delete, and/or correct the personal data processed by MultiSafepay. Please note that MultiSafepay can only grant these rights provided the data is processed is not based on a legal obligation. If you wish to enforce any of these rights, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://www.multisafepay.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#bbdfdacfdacbc9d4cfded8cfd2d4d5fbd6ced7cfd2c8dadddecbdac295d8d4d6 "Opens internal link in current window"). MultiSafepay will take action as soon as possible, but at least within four weeks. For security reasons and to establish the legitimacy or your request or complaint, we may ask for proof of identity. Please note your rights under the GDPR as stated below:

  * The right to access personal data
  * The right to correct/rectify personal data
  * The right to ask for removal of personal data
  * The right to limit the use of your personal data
  * The right to forward a complaint (see below)

If you think the service or answer received from MultiSafepay are not satisfactory, you can forward a complaint to the Dutch Data Protection Authority (DPA). You can find more information [here](https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/en "Opens internal link in current window"). 

## How do we protect personal data?

MultiSafepay acts as a 'controller' according to the new European legislation on data protection. Protecting your personal data is of primary importance to MultiSafepay. Therefore, we will take all appropriate measures, both technical and organizational, to prevent unauthorized access/modification, loss, unwanted disclosure, and improper use. If you are convinced that your data has not been properly secured or lawfully processed, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://www.multisafepay.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#492d283d28393b263d2c2a3d20262709243c253d203a282f2c392830672a2624 "Opens internal link in current window"). We will take any actionable action, within reason, to solve the problem. For security reasons, we may ask proof of identity. 

## Disclaimer

For more information, you can refer to the MultiSafepay [Disclaimer](https://www.multisafepay.com/disclaimer/#c341 "Opens internal link in current window"). 

## Changes in the privacy policy 

Please note that in order to be compliant to different laws and regulations or for any other eligible reason, we reserve the right to apply changes to this privacy policy at any time. 

Data Protection Officer and contact information 

If you have any question about this privacy policy in order to enforce one of your rights, or if you feel any of your data is abused, poorly secured, incorrectly processed, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://www.multisafepay.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#294d485d48595b465d4c4a5d40464769445c455d405a484f4c594850074a4644 "Opens internal link in current window") or by phone at +31 (0)208500553 and refer to our Data Protection Officer, Ruud Jonk.
